여보세요?
Hello.
새 직장 너무 좋아!
I love my new job!
- 목 터지겠다
- 너무 좋아서 그래!
- Honey, you're screaming.
- You bet your ass I am!
환상적인 출근 첫날이었어!
I just had the best first day ever!
부엌이 알레산드로 보다
2배나 넓어!
The kitchen?
Twice as big as Allessandro's.
잘됐네
Oh, that's great.
얼마나 깨끗한지 알아? 보건위생국
수준이 아니라 모니카 수준이야!
And clean? Not just health
department-clean, Monica-clean!
굉장한걸
Awesome.
사람들도 너무 좋아!
Oh, and the people are so nice.
제프리라는 사람이 있어
지배인인데
There's this one guy, Jeffrey,
he's the maitre d'.
자기도 정말 좋아 할거야
Chandler, you will love him!
장담하는데 내가 아는
사람중에 제일 웃겨!
He is without a doubt
the funniest guy I have ever met!
프렌즈 시즌 9
'애보는 남자'
- 너무 좋아요
- 그래요
- This is nice.
- I know.
- 두손 다 필요해요?
- 그런것 같아요
- You need both hands for that?
- Yeah, I kind of do.
자요
Well, how's this?
그동안 여기둬요
Are you sure that's sweet enough?
둘이 손 붙잡고 있네?
Look at you two holding hands.
서로 진지하게 생각하는 거야?
Is this getting serious?
아직 그런 얘기 안해봤나보지?
Have you not talked about it yet?
내가 이러니까
되게 불편하지?
Am I making you uncomfortable?
나보다 몸집만 컸어도
나 한대 쳤을거야, 그치?
If you were bigger you'd hit me.
대신 사과할게요
I'm sorry.
우리 그런 얘기 나누기엔
너무 빠른데 왜저러나 몰라
It's obviously way too early
for us to be having that conversation.
- 빠른가요?
- 아닌가? 빨라요?
- Is it?
- Maybe not. Is it?
이혼 후
When I got divorced..
다른 사람에게 이런 감정
느낄수 있을 거라곤 상상 못했어요
I didn't think I'd feel this way about
someone for a really long time.
당신같은 사람 만날 거라고도
생각 못했구요
Then again, I didn't think I'd meet
someone like you. And..
너무 빠를지도 모르지만
이거 받아줘요
This may be crazy-soon,
but I want you to have this.
아니, 이건 껌이네
No, not.. That's gum.
5달러잖아!
이럴때 기분 좋지 않아요?
Oh, five bucks!
I love it when that happens, you know?
- 꼭 공돈 생긴것 같아서..
- 계속 뒤져보지 그래요?
- You don't know it's there..
- I know. Keep digging.
알았어요
Sorry.
열쇠네요?
It's a key.
솔직히 난 5달러가
더 좋은데
To be honest, I think I'd prefer
the five dollars.
- 내 아파트 열쇠예요
- 와!
- It's to my apartment.
- Wow!
피비와 마이크
엄청난 발전이네요!
Big step for Phoebe and Mike.
피비도 나한테 열쇠를
줄 필요는..
I don't want you to feel like you
have to give me your key..
- 주고 싶어요
- 고마워요!
- No, I want to.
- Thank God.
나 지금까지 이런사람
만나본적 없었어요
Wow. I was starting to think
I'd never meet someone that..
열쇠 주고 싶은 사람
I wanted to do this with.
여기 있어요
Here you go.
- 근사하죠?
- 정말 그래요
- This is cool.
- It really is.
그러게! 요 작은게
문을 연다니 말야!
I know it. It is amazing.
These little things open doors!
전 한달후에
출근할 예정이지만
So I don't go back to work
for another four weeks..
엠마가 익숙해질수 있게
but we would like our nanny
to start right away..
지금부터 유모를 쓸 생각이에요
so that Emma could get
a chance to know her.
현명한 판단이에요
I think that's really smart.
바뀐 생활에 잘 적응할 수록
아기한테도 좋은 거니까요
The easier we can make the
transition for her the better.
좋아요
That's great. Great.
- 우리한테 물어볼것 없나요?
- 없어요
- So do you have any questions for us?
- Not really.
좋아요
와줘서 고맙습니다
All right. Well, thank you
so much for coming.
- 고마워요
- 반가웠어요
- Thank you.
- It was really nice to meet you.
- 전화드리죠
- 잠깐만요
- We will call you.
- Oh, you know, wait.
질문이 하나 있어요
I do have one question.
가끔 약물검사를 하나요?
Do you guys do random drug testing?
생각해 본적 없는데요
Boy, we hadn't really thought of that.
다행이에요, 혹시 검사할거면
3일전에 미리 말해주세요
That's cool. But if you do,
I'm gonna need three days' notice.
알겠습니다
Okey-dokey!
이러다 유모 못구하겠다!
We're never gonna find a nanny.
걱정마
아직 지원자가 더 있어
Come on, Rach. We will. I promise.
We have more interviews.
아니다 싶으면 첫번째
지원자에 대해 다시 생각하지
Worse comes to worst, we can always
reconsider the first one we met with.
- 브래지어 안입은 금발여자?
- 금발이었어?
- What, the blond with no bra?
- She was blond?
잠깐만요
Just a sec.
이사람 이름은 샌디야
Okay, this one's name is Sandy.
유아 교육을 전공했대
She's got a degree in
Early Childhood Education.
전에 일하던 집에서는
3년동안 애를 봐줬구
She worked for her last family
for three years.
안녕하세요?
샌디라고 합니다
Hi. I'm Sandy.
그리고 좀 남자 같군
And she's a little mannish.
어머나, 데이빗!
Oh, my God! David!
- 바쁜데 찾아온 건가요?
- 아뇨, 잘 왔어요! 들어와요
- Is this a bad time?
- No, it's a great time! Come in!
어쩜!
Wow! Hi!
웬일이에요?
민스크에서 돌아온 거예요?
Oh, my gosh! What are you doing here?
Are you back from Minsk?
- 몇일 있다 가야해요
- 오!
Just for a couple of days.
연구비 지원해준 사람들한테
I'm here to explain to the people
who gave us our grant..
돈은 다 써버렸지만
아무 결과도 없는 지금 상황이
why it's a positive thing that
we've spent all their money..
왜 긍정적인지
설명하러 왔어요
and accomplished nothing.
무슨 상관이에요?
덕분에 돌아왔잖아요
Who cares? It got you here.
그래요
공항에서 택시를 탔더니
It got me to New York.
Then I got in a cab at the airport..
어디로 가냐고 묻더군요
and the guy said, "Where to?"
그런데 피비 주소를 댔어요
생각도 못했던 일인데..
I just gave him your address.
I didn't even think about it.
짐은 어디 있어요?
Where's your luggage?
이런!
Damn it.
택시회사에 전화할게요
All right, I'll call the cab company.
잠깐, 전화는 나중에 하고
거기 잠깐 서볼래요?
We can call them later.
Can you just stand there for a moment?
와!
Boy.
러시아 표현중에
이런게 있어요
There's an old Russian expression
that goes:
대충 번역하면 이래요
Roughly translated, that means:
"저걸봐! 와!"
"This thing that I'm looking at: Wow."
고마워요
Thank you.
지금 꼴이 말이 아닌데..
아니, 꽤 괜찮네요
You should see me when..
Actually, no, I look pretty good.
무슨 소리예요?
Are you kidding?
누군가를 오랫동안 못보면
You know, when you don't see
someone for a long time..
머릿속에서 그 모습을 상상하죠
you build them up in your head,
you start thinking:
하지만 실제모습이 상상만큼
아름다운 사람은 없어요
"Come on, don't be crazy,
nobody's that beautiful."
하지만 피비는 달라요
But, well, you are.
그런데 지금 만나고 있는
사람 있나요?
Well, so are you seeing anyone?
아뇨
No.
난 정말 나쁜 인간이야!
I'm just the worst person ever!
마이크와 사귄다는 말을
대체 왜 못한거야!
How can I not tell David
that I'm seeing Mike?
데이빗이 기회를 안준거겠지
Maybe he didn't give you a chance.
"만나는 사람 있어요?" 하길래
"아뇨" 그랬는걸!
He said, "Are you seeing someone?"
and I said, "No."
- 네 속마음이 나온거 아냐?
- 그러게
Well, that would've been your window.
데이빗의 눈을 보면서
이런 생각이 들더라구
I mean, I don't know.
I was looking in his eyes..
"맙소사! 데이빗이다!
데이빗이 왔어!"
and I was just thinking,
"Oh, my God, it's David. David's here."
그이는 너무 매력적이거든!
He's so irresistible.
- 정말? 그 과학자가?
- 그러는 챈들러는?
- Really? The scientist guy?
- Really? Chandler?
얘기나 계속해
Continue.
그런데 그게 다가 아냐
Then it gets worse..
데이빗한테 내일 저녁에
만나자고 해버렸어!
because I told him
I would see him tomorrow night.
- 피비!
- 나도 알아! 난 사악해!
- Phoebe!
- I know! Evil!
하지만 나 마이크 많이 좋아해
둘이 잘되고 있다구!
I like Mike so much, you know?
It's just going really well. Oh, my God!
마이크와 열쇠 교환한 날
Isn't it ironic that David
would show up..
데이빗이 돌아오다니
아이러니지?
on the same day that
you and Mike exchange keys?
평생을 아이러니 찾아 헤맸으니
Yeah. You know, and given
my lifelong search for irony..
내가 지금 얼마나 행복하겠니!
you can imagine how happy I am!
- 어떡할거야?
- 데이빗에게
- What are you gonna do?
- I mean, I guess I just have to..
우리 사이는
희망이 없다고 얘기해야지
tell David that nothing
can happen between us.
정말 희망이 없나?
Unless I don't.
너무 복잡한 문제 아니니?
You know, complicated moral situation?
- 뭐가 옳고 그른지 모르겠어
- 데이빗한테 얘기해!
- No right, no wrong?
- You have to tell David.
알았어! 이런 얘기는
조이랑 해야하는 건데!
I knew I should've had this conversation
with Joey.
아는 사람중에 제일 웃기다구?
Funniest guy she's ever met.
웃기는건 내 전공 아냐?
I'm funny, right?
네가 뭘 알겠냐?
문짝 주제에
What do you know? You're a door.
넌 '똑똑, 누구세요?'하는
농담거리 밖에 안돼
You just like knock-knock jokes.
안에 들어가서 써먹어야지!
Save it for inside.
오클라호마는 정말 재밌어!
'일찍 정착한 주'라고들 부르잖아?
So Oklahoma's a crazy place. You know,
they call it the Sooner State.
나도 다른 어느 주에서보다
'일찍' 정착했다구!
Frankly, I'd sooner be in any other state!
오클라호마의 프라이팬
손잡이 알지?
And what's with Oklahoma
having a panhandle?
다른 주에도 그런게 있을까?
Can all states have stuff like that?
난 와이오밍 주의
허리띠 지역 출신이죠!
Hey, yeah, I'm from the waistband
of Wyoming.
하지만 7살 됐을때
가랑이 쪽으로 이주했어요!
But when I was 7,
we headed over to the crotch.
기내 산소압이 너무 높았어?
Was your cabin pressurized?
제발 털사 사람들 말투
어떠냐고 묻지마
And don't get me started on the way
the people from Tulsa talk.
안물을게
Okay.
'모두 다'를 줄여서 '모다'라고 한다니까
두 단어를 붙여서 말한다니까
What's with the word "y'all"? You know,
just two words just pushed together?
우리도 그렇게 해볼까?
말을 다 그렇게 하면 재밌을 거야
Are we all allowed to do that?
Because if so, I say why stop there?
'새 강아지'는 '새아지'
You know, your new poodle
could be your noodle.
'튀긴 닭'은 '튀닭'
And fried chicken could be fricken.
웨이터! 여기 '튀닭' 주세요!
Waiter? Waiter, excuse me,
I'll have the fricken!
'튀닭'은 정말 웃기지?
See, that's funny with the fricken, right?
아니, 오늘 식당 사람이 한 얘기가
생각나서 웃었어
No, it just reminds me of something
this guy did today at work.
제프리라고
웃긴 남자 있다고 얘기했지?
I told you about that funny guy, Jeffrey,
right?
드디어 나왔군
Yeah, he came up.
그 남자가 그런식으로 웃겨
자기가 직접 들어야 하는데
Well, he did this bit.
You probably had to be there..
'라이자 미넬리가 우리 냉장고에
갇혀서 생 닭을 먹는다'고 했거든
but it was Liza Minnelli locked
in our freezer eating a raw chicken.
- 너도 같이 있었니?
- 아니, '튀닭'이랑 비슷하게 웃겨서
- Were you there?
- No, but it sounds fricken funny.
아기를 남에게 맡기는게
얼마나 힘든 일인지 잘 알아요
I really understand how hard it's gotta be
to leave your child with another person.
심장 한쪽을 떼어놓는것
같을 거예요
I mean, it's like leaving behind
a piece of your heart.
샌디, 정말 그래요
Sandy, that's exactly what it is.
게이에요?
Are you gay?
죄송해요, 로스가 그래요
총알 날아가듯 말을 내뱉죠
I'm sorry, that's our Ross.
He's just Mr. Shoot Straight From The Hip.
괜찮아요
자주 겪는 일이니까
It's okay. I get that a lot doing what I do.
하지만 전 아니에요
약혼녀도 있구요
But I am straight. I'm engaged, actually.
- 이름은 딜리아예요
- 예쁜 이름이네요
- Her name's Delia.
- That's pretty.
그럼 그냥 애보는
남자란 말예요?
So you're just, like,
a guy who's a nanny.
어떤 사람들은 그걸좀
이상하다고 생각하죠
I realize how it's a bit unorthodox
for some people.
하지만 아이 돌보는 것만큼
보람있는 일은
But I really believe the most satisfying
thing you can do with your life..
없다고 믿어요
is take care of a child.
어련하겠어요
Okay.
전에 일한 집에서도 그랬죠
Like at my last job.
다니엘이 3주 됐을 때부터
그앨 보기 시작했어요
I met Daniel when he was
3 weeks old.
그애가 멋진 아이로
자라는 모습을 봤죠
And I got to watch him grow
into this awesome person.
떠날때 "금방 또
만날거야"라고 했더니
When I left, I said, "I'll see you soon."
이러더군요, "스카댄디?"
And he said to me, "Skadandy?"
걔가 절 그렇게 불렀어요
That was his name for me.
"전 아저씨를 매일
만날 거예요, 마음속에서.."
"I'll see you every day right in.."
애들이 원래 그런
헛소리를 잘하죠
- It's okay.
- Yeah, kids say all kinds of crap.
기저귀를 갈아줘야겠어요
Oh, God, she must need
her diaper changed.
- 괜찮다면 제가할게요
- 그래주면 고맙죠
- I can take care of that, if you want.
- That would be great.
그런데, 이 공룡 장난감은
신생아에겐 부적절한 겁니다
Just so you know, these dinosaur toys
aren't really age-appropriate.
내거예요
They're mine.
어른에게도 부적절하고요
Also not age-appropriate.
너무 좋아! 마음에 들어!
I love him, I love him, I love him!
저 친구는 남자야!
Come on. Rach, he's a guy!
그게 뭐?
똑똑하고 능력 있잖아!
So what? He's smart. He's qualified.
안되는 이유 하나만 대봐
Give me one good reason
we shouldn't try him out.
너무 이상해!
Because it's weird!
왜?
Why?
아, 난 그 생각은 못했네
Wow, I never looked at it that way.
무슨 남자가 직업이
애보기냐구!
What kind of a job is that for a man?
A nanny?
그건 마치 여자가..
I mean, it's like if a woman
wanted to be..
뭐?
Yes?
왕인것 같잖아?
King?
엠마한테 직접 만든 로션을
발라줬는데 괜찮을까요?
I hope you don't mind. I used
some of my homemade lotion on Emma.
금잔화랑 벌꿀을 섞은 크림이죠
기저귀 발진을 가라앉혀 주거든요
It's a mixture of calendula and
honey cream. It'll dry that rash right up.
게다가 손에도 아주 좋아요
Plus, it keeps the hands young.
샌디, 우리 엠마를 봐주세요!
Yes! Sandy, you're hired!
잘됐네요!
That's great!
죄송해요
I'm sorry.
이렇게 환영받으면
마음이 너무 벅차서..
It's just such an emotional thing
when you're welcomed into a new family.
오, 이리와요!
Oh, God. Come here.
그럼 양성애자죠?!
You gotta be at least bi.
'풍만한 가슴'
나 농담하게 연극좀 하자
I need you to set me up for a joke.
모니카 있을때 나한테
소방차에 대해 물어봐
When Monica's around,
ask me about fire trucks.
글쎄, 나 대사 외우는건
소질 없는데
I don't know, Chandler. I'm not
so good with remembering lines.
너 그걸로 먹고사는게 아니라
천만다행이구나
Thank God your livelihood
doesn't depend on it.
그렇지?
I know, right?
그런데 왜 그래야 하는데?
Why are we doing this?
모니카가 자기네 지배인이
세상에서 제일 웃긴대
Monica says that her maitre d' is
the funniest guy she's ever met.
- 정말? 정말 그렇게 말했어?
- 그래! 내가 화내는게 이상한 거냐?
- Seriously? She actually said that?
- Yes. Am I crazy to be this upset?
- 천만에! 웃긴건 네 전공이잖아!
- 그래!
- No! Being funny's your thing!
- Yeah!
그거 없으면 완전 시체지
Without that, you just got
"lame with women"!
여기들 있었네?
Hi! There you are.
소방차!
Fire trucks!
- 안녕
- 어서 와요
- Hi.
당신 주려고 민스크에서
가져왔어요
I brought you this from Minsk.
믿기 어렵겠지만
이게 바로 레몬 보드카예요
You're not gonna belief this.
This is lemon-flavored vodka.
그런데, 여기서도 구할수 있어요
Yeah, we actually have this here.
리바이스 청바지 네개랑
바꾼건데
I traded four pairs of Levi's for that.
어쨌든 고마워요
Thanks anyway.
와! 어제보다 더욱 예쁘네요
Wow. You look even more beautiful
than you did yesterday.
키스하고 싶어요
In fact, I'm going to kiss you now.
- 오, 잠깐!
- 나 이런거 너무 어색하죠?
- Wait, wait.
- I can't get away with stuff like that.
분위기 잡힐줄 알았는데..
It sounded sexy in my head, so I..
그래서가 아니에요
No, no, it's not that.
만나는 사람 있냐고 물었을때
아니라고 대답했었죠?
Remember when you asked me if
I was seeing someone and I said no?
실은 있어요
마이크란 남자죠
Well, I am. His name's Mike.
- 진작 말해야 했는데..
- 아뇨
- I should've told you.
- No.
맞아요
Well, yeah.
미안해요, 얘기하려고 했는데
당신 눈을 보면서..
I'm sorry. I wanted to tell you,
but then I just got lost in your eyes..
잠시 잊고 있었어요
누구더라..
and I just forgot all about..
- 마이크요?
- 그래요, 맞아요
- Mike?
- Right, yes.
- 정말 미안해요
- 괜찮아요, 이해해요
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Well, it's okay. I understand.
그 남자랑 행복해요?
Well, are you happy with this guy?
- 행복해요
- 빌어먹을!
- I am happy.
- Damn it.
미안해요, 물론 난 당신이
행복하길 바라죠
I'm sorry. I don't mean that.
I want you to be happy.
나하고 말예요, 아니, 그건 너무
이기적이군요, 그 남자랑 헤어져요!
But only with me. No, that's not fair.
Who cares. Leave him.
농담이에요! 아니
진심이에요! 미안해요
I don't mean that. Yes, I do.
I'm sorry.
그만 가는게 좋겠어요
I think I should probably go.
데이빗, 이것만은 알아줘요
But, David, I just want you to know that,
you know..
이 얘기 꺼내는거 나에겐
정말 힘든 일이었어요
telling you this is one of the
hardest things I've ever had to do.
그 얘길 듣는것도
Well, just so you know..
그리 즐거운 일은 아니었어요
hearing it wasn't exactly
a Vladnik carnival, either.
- 작별 포옹은 괜찮겠죠?
- 그럼요
- Can we at least hug goodbye?
- Of course. Yeah.
뺨에 뽀뽀하는 정도는
아무 문제없을 거예요
You know, and a kiss on the cheek
wouldn't be totally inappropriate.
- 그럼요
- 그러니까..
- No. No.
- I mean..
- 민스크에서는요..
- 네?
- In Minsk?
- Yeah?
양쪽 뺨에 두번씩 하고
It's two on each cheek..
입술에 한번하죠
- and one on the lips.
- Well, if that's what they do in Minsk.
민스크에서 그렇게 한다면
그러죠, 뭐
뉴욕에서는요..
In New York, it's..
어쩜!
Oh, boy.
무슨일 있어?
Is everything all right?
아냐, 괜찮아
Oh, yeah. No, it's fine. It's fine.
샌디가.. 약혼녀에게
청혼한 얘길 해줬는데
Sandy was just telling me about how he
proposed to his fiancee..
너무 감동적이야!
and it was so beautiful.
동백꽃을 제일 좋아하거든요
그 시에 나오는..
Her favorite flower is the camellia.
From the poem..
그만! 얘기하지 말아요!
I can't hear it again!
나도 못하겠어요!
You know, I can't tell it again!
난 그 얘기 평생
못들어도 괜찮아요
And I'm fine never having heard it.
- 레이첼, 잠깐 볼래?
- 그래, 잠깐만요
- Rach, can I see you for a sec?
- Yeah. Excuse me.
저남자 우리집에 와서
벌써 세번이나 운거 알아?
Do you realize that man has cried
in our apartment three times?
내가 여기 살면서 운것도
그것보다는 적어!
I haven't cried that many times
since I moved in!
왜그래, 로스
저번에 벤이
Come on, Ross, you got a little misty
when Ben broke your I-heart-fossils mug.
"난 화석을 사랑해"라고 써진
자기 머그잔 깼을때 울뻔했잖아
그건 박물관의 동료들이
작별 선물로 준거였어
I'll have you know that was a farewell gift
from my colleagues at the museum.
- 다들 돈을 모아 사준 거라고
- 너를 무척이나 좋아했나보다
- Okay? They all chipped in for that.
- They must have all loved you very much.
샌디는 감성이 풍부한 것뿐이야
Look, Ross, Sandy's just sensitive.
That's all.
바로 그게 문제야
너무 감성적이라구!
Okay, okay. See, that is the problem.
He is too sensitive.
뭐? 우리 애 보기에
너무 감성적이란 말야?
Too sensitive to take care of our baby?
그게 아니라, 모든게..
진짜 맛있다!
No, I mean, that guy..
These are amazing!
샌디가 만든 거야!
Sandy made madeleines.
바로 이거라니까
This is exactly
what I'm talking about.
무슨 남자가 이런 섬세한
프랑스 쿠키를 굽냐구!
What kind of a guy makes delicate
French cookies?
울뚝불뚝 남자답지도 않고
They're not even butch,
manly cookies with..
덩어리도 없잖아!
You know, with chunks!
무슨 말을 해야할지 모르겠네
Well, you know,
I don't know what to say.
난 자기가 그렇게 남자다움에
목매는 사람이라곤 생각 못했어
I mean, I never thought of you as a guy
who needed his men to be men.
자기가 무슨 소한테 낙인찍다 온
카우보이도 아니고 말야
I gotta tell you, Ross, it's not like you
just came in from branding cattle.
난 적당히 감성적인 거고
저 친구는 도가 지나쳐
Hey, there's sensitive and
there's too sensitive.
뭐가 도가 지나치다는 거야?
Okay, what is too sensitive?
안돼요, 이럴순 없어요
이러면 안돼요
No, I can't. I can't do this. It's bad.
하지만 좋잖아요
좋은건 좋은 거예요
But it's nice. And nice is good.
좋은건 나쁜게 아니에요
고로, 계속 키스합시다
And good is not bad.
Ergo, we should keep kissing.
- 안돼요!
- 하지만..
- No, no. No.
- But..
고로..
Ergo.
당신이 떠나지 않았더라면
Look, David, if you had never left, then..
우린 지금쯤 함께 있겠죠
yeah, we'd probably still be together
right now.
하지만 당신은 떠났고
지금 내겐 마이크가 소중해요
But you did leave. And I'm with Mike
and I really care about him.
알았어요
Okay.
그 남자 복이 많네요
Well, he's very lucky.
고마워요
Thank you.
그럼 잘 있어요
Goodbye.
열쇠가 잘듣네!
The key works.
안녕, 마이크!
Hi, Mike.
얼굴 마사지 정말 고마워요!
And, you, thanks for the face massage!
Thank you!
레이첼이 애보는 남자
고용했다는 얘기했니?
Did Rachel tell you we hired
a male nanny?
- 잘됐어!
- 정말?
I think that's great!
그 남자가 피리 불고, 시 읊고,
마들렌 굽는단 얘기도 했어?
Did she tell you he plays the recorder,
recites poetry and bakes madeleines?
맛이 어땠어?
- How are they?
- Lighter than air, but that's not the point.
입에서 살살 녹아
하지만 요점은 그게 아냐!
레이첼이 남자 애보기를 고용했어
Rachel and I hired a male nanny.
정말?
Really?
남자 애보기도 있냐?
Guys do that?
- 괴상하네
- 고맙다!
- That's weird.
- Thank you!
- 그건 마치 여자가..
- 뭐?
- That's like a woman wanting to be..
- What?
- 여자가 뭐하는 것과 같을까?
- 그래, 어디좀 들어보자
- What's the end of that sentence?
- Yes. What is the end of that sentence?
남자 속옷 모델
A penis model!
챈들러에게 너희 지배인이
Anyway, did you tell Chandler
that some guy from work..
세상에서 제일 웃기다고 했니?
is the funniest guy you ever met?
- 그런데?
- 뭐야?!
- Yeah. So?
- Wow!
너 챈들러 몰라서 그래?
Really? Do you not know Chandler?
그래서 그렇게 이상하게 구는거야?
질투하는 거였어?
Is that why he's acting so weird?
He's jealous?
말도 안돼!
Oh, my God, that is crazy.
- It's not like I'm attracted to Jeffrey.
- So what?
- 그 남자한테 끌리는건 전혀 없어!
- 그게 뭐?
Being funny is Chandler's thing.
Like Ross' thing is..
웃기는건 챈들러 전공이란 말야
마치 로스의 전공이..
과학?
Science?
학구적? 좋은 아빠?
Academia? Being a good father?
그게 아냐..
그걸 그렇게 신경 쓰다니
이해가 안돼
- I can't believe he's that upset.
- Are you kidding?
생각해봐, 그건 마치
챈들러가 너보다
That's like Chandler saying he met someone
who was more uptight than you.
더 까다로운 여자를
만났다는 것과 같아
뭐라고?
- Excuse me?
- I'm sorry. Sorry. More controlling than you.
알았어, 너보다
더 지배욕이 강한 사람
- 그래야지
- 알았어, 알았다구
- Well, that's better.
- Yeah, okay.
어땠든 네가 수습 잘해
You have to do some damage control.
그녀석..
Because he's feeling like..
무슨 얘기하고 있었어?
What are you guys talking about?
우리 애보기로 남자 고용했어
Rachel and I hired a male nanny.
남자가 애보기야?
You got a man who's a nanny?
그럼 '남보기'인가?
You got a "manny"?
그냥 남자 애보기는 괜찮은데
You know, I don't mind a male nanny..
젖까지 물린다면
문제가 다르지
but I do draw the line
at male wet nurse.
자기 진짜 웃긴다!
You are on a roll, mister!
너희 있는줄 알았으면
피자 더 사오는 건데
If I'd known you guys were coming over,
I would've brought more pizza.
됐어! 그만!
웃겨서 눈물이 다 나와!
Okay! Okay! Stop it, you!
You stop it!
그게 뭐가 웃긴데?
What is so funny about that?
모니카?
Monica?
몰라, 그냥 자기 말하는
방식이 웃겨
I don't know, it's..
Just the way you say it.
자기 원래 웃기잖아
재치있고 웃긴 남자!
I mean, you're funny. You have
that funny thing. You're a funny guy!
모니카한테 그 얘기 한거야?
Did you tell her what we talked about?
그래
불쌍해서 웃은거야?
억지로 웃었어?
So those were pity laughs?
Pity laughs?!
내말 들어봐
Honey, listen.
제프리에 대해서
신경 쓸거 없어
You have nothing to worry about
with Jeffrey.
그래? 그 인간
나보다 더 웃겨?
Oh, yeah? Is he funnier than me?
자기랑은 다르게 웃겨
Well, you're different funny.
자긴 좀더 비꼬는 식이구..
I mean, you're more sarcastic.
그 사람은 말투랑
흉내내기, 짧은 시로 웃겨
Well, he does bits and impressions
and limericks.
나도 시 지을수 있어!
I do limericks.
"챈들러라는
한 사내가 있었네"
There once was a man named Chandler
whose wife made him die inside.
"그의 아내는 그의 속을
뒤집어 놓았네!"
자기가 얼마나 재미있는데!
Honey, you know I think you're hilarious.
지난주에 자기가 해준
농담 말야
You know that joke
you told me last week?
제리 루이스와 졸린 눈을 한
여자 이야기 말야
The one about Jerry Lewis
and the girl with the lazy eye.
웃겨 죽는줄 알았어
That slayed me.
그거 내가 지어낸 건데
너한테 전해준 거잖아!
Hey! I made up that joke
and told it to you.
- 낄때 안낄때 못가리는 거야
- 맞아, 그게 내 전공이야
- Not knowing when to shut up.
- Yep, that's my thing.
이 열쇠 몇 남자나
가지고 있죠?
So how many guys have your key?
아뇨, 그런게 아니에요
It's not as bad as it looks.
옛날 친구에게
작별 인사하는 중이었어요
I was saying goodbye to an old friend.
저사람 입에 피비의
립스틱이 묻었는데요?
Your lipstick's on his mouth.
그, 그건 우연히 같은 색을
바른 것뿐입니다
We just happen to wear the same shade.
실은.. 데이빗과
여러해 전에 사귀었어요
No, David and I did used to go out.
데이빗은 지금 민스크에 살아요
뉴욕에 며칠 다니러 왔대요
But years ago. And he lives in Minsk.
He's only in town for a couple days.
- 두사람 혹시..?
- 아뇨!
- Did you..?
- No. No.
- 키스했어요?
- 네, 했어요
- Kiss him?
- Oh, well, yeah.
하지만 피비는 그쪽을
정말로 좋아해요
Yes, but..
Look, she really likes you.
사실은, 굉장히 멋진 키스 도중에
피비가 그만 뒀어요..
In fact, she stopped
what was a pretty amazing kiss.
- 데이빗, 데이빗
- 괜찮아요, 끝까지 들어봐요
- David, David, David.
- No, no. He should hear this.
자기가 얼마나 행운아인지
모르는것 같군요
I don't think you realize
just how lucky you are, fella.
- 삿대질하지 말아요!
- 왜요?
- Don't point your finger at me!
- Why?
하면 어쩔건데?
What are you gonna do about it?
어쩔건지 보여주지!
Well, I'll show you
what I'm gonna do about it.
- 어, 그래?
- 맛좀 볼래?
- Oh, really? Really?
- You want some of that?
그만! 그만!
두사람 다치기 전에 그만둬요!
Stop it! Stop it!
Before someone gets really hurt!
데이빗, 어서가요
Here, David, you should just go.
알았어요
All right.
내가 민스크에서 다시 돌아올땐
조심하는게 좋을거요
But if I ever do come back from Minsk,
well, you just better watch out.
내가 민스크에 가는 날엔
당신이야말로 조심해요!
- If I go to Minsk, you better watch out.
- Oh, you're going to Minsk?
오, 민스크에 올거예요?
- 갈수도 있죠!
- 정말?
- Well, I might.
- Really?
그럼 봄에 와요
그때가 제일 좋으니까
Well, if you do, come in the spring.
It's just lovely there.
그렇다고 하더군요
I've heard that, actually.
됐어요, 그만가요
Okay, well, guys?
- 잘있어요, 피비
- 안녕
- Goodbye, Phoebe.
- Bye.
- 사람 성격테스트 해요?!
- 알았어요
- Hey, what, are you kidding me?
- Right-o. Right-o.
피비를 잘 돌봐줘요
Take good care of her.
정말 미안해요
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
열쇠 다시 돌려달라고 해도
할말 없어요
If you want your key back,
I totally understand.
- 다신 이런일 없을거죠?
- 그럼요, 절대로!
- It's never gonna happen again, right?
- Right. Never. I swear.
혹시 민스크에 올일 있으면..
내 전화번호예요
I just want to say, if you do ever
come to Minsk, that's my number.
러시아 스타일로
환영해 줄게요
We'll party up Vladnik-style.
와! 재밌는데!
Yeah! All right!
로스, 이것봐! 샌디가
'십자가빵' 노래 부는법 가르쳐줬어!
Hey, Ross! Check it out!
Sandy taught me "Hot Cross Buns"!
그래?
'세마리 눈먼 생쥐' 같던데?
Really? Sounded like "Three Blind Mice."
- 아냐, 그건 이렇지
- 하기만 해봐!
- "Three Blind Mice" goes like this.
- I swear to God.
- 인형놀이 할사람?
- 저요! 나 할래!
- Who's up for puppets?
- Me! I'm up for puppets!
킁킁이 아저씨한테
Well, please welcome:
인사할까요!
The Snufflebumps!
꿈틀이는 누가 할까?
또 투덜이는 누가 할까?
Who wants to be Mr. Wigglemunch and
who's gonna be the Grumpus?
이봐요, 2개월밖에 안된 애가
어떻게 인형극을 이해하겠어요!
How exactly is a 2-month-old
supposed to appreciate puppets?
물체의 움직임과 색깔이 뇌 발달에
도움을 준다는 연구 결과가 있어요
Studies show that the movement and
colors help their cerebral development.
웃기는 인형은 순전히
우리 재미를 위해서지만요
The whimsical characters are just for us.
나 꿈틀이 할래요!
I want to be Mr. Wigglemunch!
내가 미쳐!
Oh, my God.
투덜이는 누가 할지 뻔하네요
Well, I guess we know who's
gonna be the Grumpus!
- 너무 무례한거 아냐?
- 미안해
- That was kind of rude.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
샌디와 킁킁이한테
미안하다고 전해줘
Please apologize to Sandy
and the Snufflebumps for me.
- 샌디는 자기 일을 하는것 뿐이야!
- 어쩌지?
- You know, he was just doing his job.
- You know what?
저 남자 유모한테
반하지 않은건 나뿐인것 같군!
I'm sorry I'm the only one who isn't
in love with Gary Poppins out there.
나 도저히 못참겠어!
But I just.. I can't go through with this.
- 로스!
- 나라면
- Come on.
- No! You know what?
자기가 이렇게 불편해하는 일
강요하지 않을거야
I would never force you to hire someone
you were this uncomfortable with.
그건 그래
That's true.
고마워
Thank you.
해고하려면 자기가 말해!
You want to fire him,
so you have to go do it.
봤죠, 꿈틀이? 그래서
함께 나누는게 중요한 거예요
So you see, Wigglemunch,
that's why it's important to share.
정말 샌디한테
배우는게 많아요!
I am learning so much from you.
나 갈께
Well, I'm off to Tulsa.
지배인더러
웃기는 농담 있으면
So if your maitre d' friend
has any funny Oklahoma jokes..
이메일 하라고 해
www.하나도 안웃겨.com
tell him to e-mail me at
www-dot-ha-ha-not-so-much-dot-com!
신경쓰지마
Honey, you can relax.
어제 제프리가 남녀 차별하는
심한 농담을 했어
Last night at work Jeffrey
told this really sexist joke.
- 그후론 하나도 안웃기더라
- 정말?
- After that, not so funny anymore.
- Really?
그래야지!
머리를 잘써야 한다니까!
See, that's the thing.
You gotta keep it smart, people!
비행기 놓치겠다
사랑하는거 알지?
Don't miss that flight.
You know I love you.
그럼
I love you too.
- 친구야, 나 간다
- 잘다녀와
- And I like you as a friend.
- Right.
- 잘가
- 안녕
- See you later.
- See you.
- 지배인이 진짜 그런 농담했어?
- 아니, 여전히 웃겨
- Did the guy really make that joke?
- No, he still kills me.
어젠 어찌나 웃기던지
오줌까지 찔끔 나왔다니까
Last night he had me laughing so hard,
I swear a little pee came out.
지금 말할게
Here goes.
못보겠어!
엘모를 해고하는거 같아!
I can't watch. It's like firing Elmo.
샌디?
Sandy? Hi.
- 네
- 할..
- Hi.
- We..
얘기가 있어요
We kind of need to talk.
그만 와주면 좋겠어요
I'm afraid it's not working out.
레이첼과 난 샌디가 엠마를
아주 잘봐준다고 생각해요
I mean, Rachel and I think you are great
with Emma.
- 단지 '우리'는..
- 난 빼! 난 아냐!
- We just feel..
- You! You feel!
'난' 단지..
I just feel..
샌디하고 잘맞지 않는것 같아요
미안해요
that the chemistry isn't right.
I'm sorry.
좋은 추천서를 써줄게요
We're more than happy to give you
a good recommendation.
괜찮아요
애 봐달라는 집이 많았어요
No, that's okay. I had a lot of offers
from other families.
이댁을 선택한건..
I just picked you guys because..
- 두분이 제일 좋았기 때문이죠
- 로스, 자긴 벌받을 거야!
- I liked you the best.
- Oh, damn you, Geller!
어쨌든 감정 상하지 않고
얘기가 돼서 다행이네요
Anyway, well I'm glad
there's no hard feelings.
네, 괜찮아요
누구든 편한분과 함께 지내야죠
None at all. You need to be happy
with whoever is in your home.
그런데 말해줄수 있나요?
Although, if you don't mind telling me..
뭐가 문제죠? 고칠건 고쳐야
앞으로 도움이 되거든요
what was the problem? Maybe it's
something I can work on in the future.
샌디는 아무 문제없어요
내가 문제죠
No, you know, it's nothing you did.
It's my issue.
무슨 문제인데요?
What is it?
말해줘요
Please?
난 샌디처럼 감성이 풍부한 남자
체질적으로 불편해요
You know, I'm just not that comfortable
with a guy who's as sensitive as you.
그럴수 있죠
That's fair.
그런데 자신이
왜 그렇다고 생각해요?
Although, can I ask,
why do you think that is?
왜냐구요? 글쎄..
Why? I don't know.
아버지 때문일걸요?
Maybe because of my father?
아버진 터프가이 타입이었는데
You know, when I was growing up,
he was a tough guy.
난 어렸을때 지금처럼
운동을 잘하지 못했어요
You know, and as a kid,
I wasn't the athlete I am now.
나 스쿼시도 친단 말야!
I play squash!
아버지가 날 너무 감성적이라고
생각하는것 같았어요
Anyway, I always got the feeling
he thought I was too sensitive.
힘들었겠군요
That must have been hard.
힘들었어요
It was hard.
하루는 내방에서
공룡을 가지고 노는데..
I remember I was in my bedroom,
playing with my dinosaurs..
놀면서 공부도 했어요
Playing and learning.
아버지가 오셔서 이랬어요
"뭐하는 거냐!"
And my father walks in and says,
"What are you doing with those things?
"넌 대체 왜 그모양이지? 진짜
남자애들처럼 밖에 나가서 놀아!"
What's wrong with you? Why aren't you
outside playing like a real boy?"
- 로스도 진짜 남자예요!
- 내말이 그말이에요!
- But you are a real boy.
- I know I am!
여름에 어깨 끈 달린
쫄티 입으면 안되나요?
And when it's summer and it's hot,
why can't you wear a tank top?!
괜찮아요, 우는건 좋은 거예요
엉엉 소리내서 울어요
It's all right. Crying is good.
It lets the boo-hoos out.
아직 더 남았어요!
Here comes some more!
엠마, 너도 이 다음에 크면
성숙한 아가씨가 될게다, 네 아빠처럼
Emma, one day you're gonna grow up
and be a big girl, just like your daddy.
절대로 가라앉지 않는
배가 뭘까요?
And what's the one kind of boat
that can never ever sink?
- 뭐죠?
- 우정!
- What kind?
- A friend ship!
우와! 멋지다!
Wow! You blow my mind!
가야겠어요
I gotta go.
- 얼마주면 되죠?
- 20달러
- How much do I owe you?
- Twenty bucks.
이렇게 싼 대학 있음
나와 보라 그래!
It's like the cheapest college ever!
- 내일 봐요
- 잘가요, 스카댄디
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Okay, bye-bye, Skadandy.